Guide to the Montana Livestock Sanitary Board Records 1907-1967
Montana Historical Society
- Montana Livestock Sanitary Board
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence
    - Board of Stock Commissioners, Livestock Commission, Recorder of Marks and Brands (includes secretary's report, undated; list of printed forms used by board, 1921; contract of cattle sale J.L. Selway to Dunbar and DeVries, 1912), 1907-1923 (Box-folder 4 / 77)
  - Financial Records
    - Balance sheets, 1917-1919 (Box-folder 4 / 78)
    - Budget and payroll ledger (by numbered fund), 1932-1934, 1937-1938 (Box-folder 5 / 1)
    - Budget and payroll ledger (by numbered fund), 1943-1951 (Volume Vol. 1)
    - Budget and payroll ledger (by numbered fund), 1951-1954 (Box-folder 5 / 2)
    - Budget and payroll ledger (by numbered fund), 1955-1957 (Volume Vol. 2)
    - Budget and payroll ledger (by numbered fund), 1958-1965 (Box-folder 6 / 1)
    - Budget and payroll ledger (by numbered fund), 1965-1968 (Volume Vol. 3)
    - Journals, 1926-1937 (Volume Vol. 4-8)
    - Record of income from taxes on livestock, etc., 1956-1963 (Volume Vol. 9)
  - Legal Documents
    - Memoranda of agreement (re blood testing of cattle for Bang's Disease), 1934 (Box-folder 7 / 1)
    - Memoranda of understanding (re eradication of sheep and cattle scabies), 1922-1937 (Box-folder 7 / 2)
  - Legislative Materials
    - Proposed legislation, 1957-1959 (Box-folder 7 / 3)
  - Minutes
    - Minutes of Board meetings (also includes scattered minutes of Montana Livestock Commission), 1956-1959 (Box-folder 7 / 4)
    - Organizational charts and descriptions of duties, circa 1957 (Box-folder 7 / 5)
  - Press Releases
    - Press releases, 1959 (Box-folder 7 / 6)
  - Reports
    - Annual reports of Board (includes report of State Veterinary Surgeon, 1919), 1919-1928 (Box-folder 7 / 7)
    - "Comparative statement showing increase in work from 1909-1916" (Box-folder 7 / 8)
    - Mastitis testing reports: Lake County, 1950 (Box-folder 7 / 9)
    - Weekly field reports of Dr. John C. Boyd (Lewistown), 1915-1916 (Box-folder 8 / 1)
    - Weekly field reports of R.C. Duffey, scabies control officer (Fowler), 1917 (Box-folder 8 / 2)
    - Weekly field reports of Dr. A.J. Du Frene (Glendive), 1915-1916 (Box-folder 8 / 3)
    - Weekly field reports of Dr. Nelson T. Gunn (Butte, Helena), 1916 (Box-folder 8 / 4)
    - Weekly field reports of Dr. L. Minugh (Harlem), 1918 (Box-folder 8 / 5)
    - Weekly field reports of Dr. John J. Mitchell (many locations), 1915-1916 (Box-folder 8 / 6)
    - Weekly field reports of Dr. Fred Moran (Fairfield), 1917-1918 (Box-folder 8 / 7)
    - Weekly field reports of Dr. E.D. Nash (Helena); Deputy State Veterinary Surgeon Certificate, 1913, 1917-1918 (Box-folder 8 / 8)
    - Weekly field reports of Dr. J.W. Richardson (Malta), 1915-1916 (Box-folder 8 / 9)
    - Weekly field reports of Dr. N.B. Smith (Billings), 1915-1916 (Box-folder 8 / 10)
    - Weekly field reports of Dr. C.H. Wight (Great Falls), 1916 (Box-folder 8 / 11)
    - Weekly field reports of Dr. Howard F. Wilkens (many locations), 1916-1918, 1940-1944 (Box-folder 8 / 12)
    - Summaries of reports, 1915-1916, 1921-1922 (Box-folder 8 / 13)
  - Speeches and Writings
    - Clayton V. Berg, "Lewis and Clark County mosquito investigation", 1958 (Box-folder 8 / 14)
    - John W. Black, "The Montana Livestock Commission and Livestock Sanitary Board", undated (Box-folder 8 / 15)
    - Lyman Brewster, "Brucellosis: personal, statewide, and national"; "State line quarantine", 1957, 1959 (Box-folder 8 / 16)
    - G.C. Halver, "Salt poisoning in range cattle", 1956 (Box-folder 8 / 17)
    - James J. Hurry, "Attention: poultrymen", 1957 (Box-folder 8 / 18)
    - J.W. Safford, miscellaneous articles and talks (re brucellosis, bovine tuberculosis, leptospirosis, livestock disease protection, work of Livestock Sanitary Board, scrapie, etc.), 1957-1959 (Box-folder 8 / 19)
  - Subject File
    - Bang's Disease cases, 1939-1941 (Box-folder 8 / 20)
    - Feeding phosphorous supplement to cattle in pasture 4, Prairie County, 1953 (Box-folder 8 / 21)
    - Salvage receipts (re reimbursement for slaughtered animals) [file 017.24], 1921-1922 (Box-folder 8 / 22)
    - State ex rel. Dr. W. Edwin Stahl and the Montana Livestock Sanitary Board vs. Robert R. Peterson, Moiese, et al. (re illegal sale of dairy products), 1959-1961 (Box-folder 8 / 23)
    - State Laboratory Building Commission (includes minutes, legislative materials, etc.), 1956-1957 (Box-folder 8 / 24)
  - Miscellany
    - Applications, 1920-1922 (Box-folder 8 / 25)
    - "Assignment of duties of Livestock Sanitary Board office and laboratory personnel", undated (Box-folder 8 / 26)
    - "Big Hole area cattle dipped for scabies", 1943 (Box-folder 8 / 27)
    - Examination for Deputy State Veterinary Surgeon applicants, circa 1918 (Box-folder 8 / 28)
    - Forms, circular letters, etc. (re brucellosis, tuberculosis, Bang's Disease, etc.), 1940s (Box-folder 8 / 29)
    - "Lambs and sheep exported from Montana and the states to which they were consigned", 1941-1942 (Box-folder 8 / 30)
    - List of cattle owners, by county, 1961-1965 (Box-folder 8 / 31)
    - List of salaried employees of the Board, 1919 (Box-folder 8 / 32)
    - List of sanitarians, lay inspectors, brucellosis technicians, poultry inspectors, board members, and artificial inseminators, 1958-1959, undated (Box-folder 8 / 33)
    - Memorandum of necrobaccillosis in sheep and cattle, 1933 (Box-folder 8 / 34)
    - Order No. 46: official charges for interstate inspections, 1921 (Box-folder 8 / 35)
    - "An Outline of animal health requirements pertaining to animals shipped to Montana", undated (Box-folder 8 / 36)
    - Phillips County (re re-certification of Phillips County by Animal Disease Eradication Division), 1962-1965 (Box-folder 8 / 37)
    - Record of inspections (lists owner, address, date of inspection, inspector, and results), 1912-1913 (Volume Vol. 10)
    - Rules and regulations (includes "Regulation No. 21" re livestock market regulation; "Regulation No. 52" re sheep shipped or trailed in Montana; and "Rules for conduct of meetings of the Livestock Commission and Livestock Sanitary Board", 1921, 1957, undated (Box-folder 8 / 38)
    - Tuberculin reactors (lists owner, address, number tested, number reacted, and origin), 1915-1916 (Box-folder 8 / 39)
    - Valley County, 1962-1965 (Box-folder 8 / 40)
  - Clippings
    - Northwestern Stockman and Farmer (re brands; annotated), 1907-1924 (Box-folder 8 / 41)
- Foot-and-mouth Disease
  - General Correspondence
    - A-R (mostly letters from ranchers, homesteaders, and others wishing to ship cattle and inquiring about foot-and-mouth quarantine), 1914-1915 (Box-folder 8 / 42-53)
    - State Veterinarians (correspondence with out-of-state state veterinarians about quarantine), 1914-1915 (Box-folder 8 / 54)
    - S-T (mostly letters from ranchers, homesteaders, and others wishing to ship cattle and inquiring about foot-and-mouth quarantine), 1914-1915 (Box-folder 8 / 55-56)
    - United States. Bureau of Animal Industry, 1914-1915 (Box-folder 8 / 57)
    - United States Stock Sanitary Association, 1914-1915 (Box-folder 8 / 58)
    - U-Y (mostly letters from ranchers, homesteaders, and others wishing to ship cattle and inquiring about foot-and-mouth quarantine), 1914-1915 (Box-folder 8 / 59)
    - Miscellaneous (includes evaluations of cattle, salary and expenses of Bureau of Animal Industry employees working on foot-and-mouth disease), 1914-1915 (Box-folder 8 / 60)
  - Miscellany
    - Certificates of appraisal of animals, 1914 (Box-folder 8 / 61)
    - Foot-and-mouth disease brochures and regulations, 1914-1915 (Box-folder 8 / 62)
- Tuberculosis
  - General Correspondence
    - Tuberculosis control: cattle, 1932-1933 (Box-folder 9 / 1-2)
    - United States Bureau of Animal Industry (includes Bureau's authorizations for 1921-1922, 1928-1929), 1921-1953, undated (Box-folder 9 / 3)
  - Legal Documents
    - Agreement for the tuberculin testing of herds of cattle under the Tuberculosis Free Herd Plan, 1932 (Box-folder 9 / 4)
  - Reports
    - "Tuberculosis eradication summary of work performed by veterinary inspectors" (includes names of inspectors, locations, and number of cattle tested), 1932-1933 (Box-folder 9 / 5)
    - "Summary of tuberculosis eradication work in cooperation with the various states", 1932-1933 (Box-folder 9 / 6)
- Transfers To Other Programs
  - Transfers
    - List of artifacts, maps, printed material, and photographs transferred to the Museum, Library Map Collection, Library, and Photo Archives respectively (Box-folder 9 / 7)